<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Genvega, AWS Cloud Automation</title>
    <description>Genvega, inc. is a AWS partner and solutions architecture company.</description>
    <link>http://www.genvega.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.genvega.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 14:16:44 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 14:16:44 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Speaking: AWS DevOps Automation @ Chicago Coder Conference</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/its_automatic-reduced.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;AWS automated development operations&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am &lt;a href=&quot;http://chicagocoderconference.com/cccsession/session-5-devops-automation-for-aws/&quot;&gt;speaking&lt;/a&gt; again! This time I am going to be at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://chicagocoderconference.com/&quot;&gt;Chicago Coder Conference&lt;/a&gt; on Monday, June 6 at 3:45. It is very exciting for me to have the chance to talk and learn from everyone else&#39;s experiences. I will be focussing specifically on &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/&quot;&gt;AWS&lt;/a&gt; and tools it provides for successful DevOps automation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Topics included:
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;1. Share AWS Learning &amp;amp; Experience&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;2. Demo/Deep Dive of AWS SDK, CloudFormation&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;3. How to Define Success for DevOps Automation&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;4. Industry Best Practices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What else would you like to learn about? I hope to see you there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 12:04:43 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.genvega.com/blog/2016/Come-see-me-at-Chicago-Coder-Conference/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.genvega.com/blog/2016/Come-see-me-at-Chicago-Coder-Conference/</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcements</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tvarit is ready for takeoff!!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/its_automatic-reduced.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;AWS automated development operations&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After weeks of burning the midnight candle, I have just released the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sdole/tvarit-maven/releases/tag/v0.1.1-alpha&quot;&gt;first working alpha&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a style=&quot;font-weight:bold&quot; href=&quot;http://www.tvarit.io&quot;&gt;Tvarit&lt;/a&gt; - a Dev Ops Automation tool for Amazon Web Services! It is in &lt;a href=&quot;http://search.maven.org/#artifactdetails%7Cio.tvarit%7Ctvarit-maven-plugin%7C0.1.1%7Cmaven-plugin&quot;&gt;maven central&lt;/a&gt;; give it a spin! I want to hear your &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sdole/tvarit-maven/issues/new&quot;&gt;feedback&lt;a /&gt;. Does it work for you? What &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sdole/tvarit-maven/blob/master/README.md&quot;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; should I add to make it clearer? 

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
In a nutshell, Tvarit enables a development team to completely automate deployment of a JEE WAR file to AWS. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;1. Tomcat 8 application server with Java 8&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;2. High availability via cross zone load balancing&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;3. Completely automated infrastructure setup and deployment&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;4. Scale horizontally using AWS&#39;s native autoscaling&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;5. Customize using cloudformation templates (or use the default setup)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Roadmap&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is already an exciting product. It can already shave of hours and hours of manual labor for a typical project running on the JEE platform! Here are some of the major enhancements I plan to make in the near future.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;1. Scale down previously running application versions&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;2. Completely customizable application server environments&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;3. Deploy with an RDS datasource with secured credentials&lt;li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;4. Automatic independent environments for test and production&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;5. Multi-app deployment and inter app-version contracts (à la micro-services)&lt;/li&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;How can you help?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many ways you can get involved. Have a feature idea on your mind? &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sdole/tvarit-maven/issues/new&quot;&gt;Suggest it&lt;/a&gt;, or submit me a pull request. Have questions? Ask me here (in the comments) or on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sdole/tvarit-maven/issues/new&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. Not sure how you can help or have other questions? &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:sdole@genvega.com?subject=I have a question about Tvarit&quot;&gt;Email me&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/sdoledotcom/&quot;&gt;tweet me&lt;/a&gt;, lets discuss!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;How can I help?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am available for supporting Tvarit and for assessing your Dev Ops automation requirements. I am also available to discuss general AWS topics at your office, with your developers. If you have not already, please check some of my other articles here or come to one of my meetup sessions. AWS is a great product that can truly bring down the costs of your IT infrastructure while improving availability and scalability of it. Ask me to find out how you can do it!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 11:04:43 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.genvega.com/blog/2016/tvarit-ready-for-takeoff/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.genvega.com/blog/2016/tvarit-ready-for-takeoff/</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcements</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Calculate TCO for storage and backup</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;What, do you think, is the simplest way to chop off a few percentage points of your IT budget? Does migrating to &lt;a href=&quot;http://aws.amazon.com/&quot;&gt;AWS cloud&lt;/a&gt; storage come to mind? If not, think again! If you need help thinking, you may be in luck. The friendly folks over at AWS recently released a new &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.backuparchive.awstcocalculator.com/&quot;&gt;TCO calculator&lt;/a&gt; for backup and archiving. It looks pretty cool; I took it for a drive earlier today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.backuparchive.awstcocalculator.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/aws-tco-calculator.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of AWS TCO calculator&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has three tabs, the &lt;strong&gt;basic&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;advanced&lt;/strong&gt; and the &lt;strong&gt;direct&lt;/strong&gt; tab. On the basic tab, you just enter the RAW storage that you currently have on-prem and a few characteristics of it, such as its y-o-y growth. Hit calculate, and AWS will show you a pretty picture of how AWS backup solutions compare with on-prem backup architectures. You can also compare the AWS solution with a colo architecture by choosing it in the drop down menu. On the Advanced tab, there are many more options to pick between warm backup and long term archival. If your organization has legal or regulatory requirements around backup, you can specify retention periods (in years or days or any term in between). On the advanced tab, you should also enter how often or how much of your data do you expect to restore and how many levels of redundancy do you want. Additionally, to truly compare on-prem costs with the cloud, the TCO calculator also allows you to enter your leverage of discounts and existing vendor relationships. This means that if you have an existing relationship with NetApp that allows you a 50% discount on volume purchases, this TCO calculator will shave that off its calculation of on prem costs. All in all, it seems well organized. Here is one of the calculations of my driving test on this calculator. I used numbers from a previous job where I was fairly conversant with data backup and archival.  
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;/images/aws-tco-calculator-test-drive.PNG&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/aws-tco-calculator-test-drive.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of AWS TCO calculator with my test drive numbers&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
This is very interesting. At the very least, it shows two things. At first, it shows a clear cut, numbers based approach that you can compare to your own operations. Secondly, it offers a financial framework to think about cloud data backup and storage. Think about hot storage, cold storage, networking, personnel and support. Don&#39;t think vendors, appliances, hardware, disks, failures and any of those things that vex you today. Great job AWS! 
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2016 11:04:43 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.genvega.com/blog/2016/Storage-and-backup-calculator/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.genvega.com/blog/2016/Storage-and-backup-calculator/</guid>
        
        
        <category>opinion</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Upload to S3 using the Amazon Java SDK!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a 10 minute video I made a few months ago about how to use the AWS Java SDK to upload any type of data to S3. It is very easy. There are a few gotchas that I explain in depth. If you like this video or have feedback, leave me a comment on this page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;404&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/5IvT4MhMuUw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 11:04:43 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.genvega.com/blog/2016/How-to-upload-to-S3-using-AWS-SDK/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.genvega.com/blog/2016/How-to-upload-to-S3-using-AWS-SDK/</guid>
        
        
        <category>how-to</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>AWS Java SDK - DevOps Automation!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I am &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/IllinoisJUGNorthwest/events/228187464/&quot;&gt;presenting&lt;/a&gt; again! This time, I will build on my previous presentation and share my personal story of how AWS SDKs promote automation of infrastructure provision. Through my experience, I truly started believing that the old way of writing software, then having someone build it, and then having someone else deploy it, test it and finally have another party move it into production just will not work. That old way of doing things is just, simply, too slow. Too slow, too expensive and too far detached from customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/automation.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image showing a retro factory with boilers and pipes indicating automation.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Consider disruption potential.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;History shows that companies that move really fast on really small budgets are usually the disruptive force in an industry. A large undertaking with consensus driven, risk averse culture only enables incremental innovation while others try to disrupt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Consider lean software enterprise.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basis of lean is in the ability to produce steady iterations of minimal innovative feature sets which allow the company to pivot or persevere. Will a long cycle SDLC process allow you to produce frequent iterations that can be A/B tested with customers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Consider customer satisfaction.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customers want service quickly, easily and continuously. Any bugs, performance problems, downtime is perceived by customers as poor customer service. How can a multi week production cycle help an enterprise fix a bug or improve performance? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;DevOps Automation - what can it do?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the basic level, DevOps Automation promises to reduce the time taken between writing a line of code and using it in production. In some enterprises, it can take up to 10 person years (yes, 10 person years). Regardless of how long it takes, most IT professionals are familiar with processes and gates that are ubiquitous in SDLC. Even as enterprises switch to agile methodology and automate many aspects of software development, they still depend on a large amount of manual work to test, move, deploy &amp;amp; operate software &amp;amp; infrastructure. With a good plan and a strategic shift in goals and cultural mindset, DevOps promises to automate all aspects - I mean all aspects - of taking software to production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;AWS - SDK and Automation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://aws.amazon.com&quot;&gt;Amazon web services&lt;/a&gt; is built, from the core, for automation. Almost all aspects of infrastructure provisioning on AWS can be done with an API call. In most cases, a DevOps Engineer can chain API calls to provision dependent infrastructure and can also utilize third party tools such as Chef, Puppet or Ansible on AWS. AWS also has products that specifically are built for automating the build lifecycle. If DevOps is a key part of your game plan you will learn about how to take it to the next level. If you want to make DevOps the center of your IT strategy, this presentation will get you started. Do not miss it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Head over to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/IllinoisJUGNorthwest/events/228187464/&quot;&gt;IJUG - NW meetup site&lt;/a&gt; for registration and venue information! Special thanks to Illinois Java Users Group for organizing this and their generous hosts &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nielsen.com/us/en.html&quot;&gt;Nielsen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2016 11:04:43 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.genvega.com/blog/2016/I-am-presenting-on-aws-devops/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.genvega.com/blog/2016/I-am-presenting-on-aws-devops/</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcements</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>AWS Certified!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The success of any AWS implementation inevitably depends on well communicated goals expressed in technical as well as commercial terms. Leaders tasked with transforming an IT organization must spend time and energy to communicate achievable targets, time frames and priorities throughout the organization. Who better to carry out this task then people whom Amazon Web Services certifies to be technically knowledgeable? To show my commitment to successful AWS implementations and to show solidarity with an IT leader&#39;s cause, I recently obtained the AWS Solutions Architect certification. This is just the first step in showcasing various levels of knowledge that Genvega and I can bring to the table for complex IT cloud projects. In future, I plan to take the AWS DevOps Engineer certification test. Watch this space!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Solutions-Architect-Associate.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image showing AWS Solutions Architect - Associate&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;About the AWS Solutions Architect Certification&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AWS &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/certification/&quot;&gt;certifications&lt;/a&gt; test the individual&#39;s ability to design, deploy and operate AWS infrastructure. In particular, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/certification/certified-solutions-architect-associate/&quot;&gt;AWS Solutions Architect certification&lt;/a&gt; tests the individual&#39;s ability to design fault tolerant, scalable systems using AWS. A Certified AWS Solutions Architect is able to analyze business requirements and select the most suitable and cost efficient system design suitable for the requirement. 
&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2016 11:04:43 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.genvega.com/blog/2016/aws-certified-solutions-architect/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.genvega.com/blog/2016/aws-certified-solutions-architect/</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcements</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
