<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Genvega, AWS Cloud Automation</title>
    <description>Genvega, inc. is a AWS partner and solutions architecture company.</description>
    <link>http://www.genvega.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.genvega.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2016 14:44:35 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2016 14:44:35 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>AWS Certified!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The success of any AWS implementation inevitably depends on well communicated goals expressed in technical as well as commercial terms. Leaders tasked with transforming an IT organization must spend time and energy to communicate achievable targets, time frames and priorities throughout the organization. Who better to carry out this task then people whom Amazon Web Services certifies to be technically knowledgeable? To show my commitment to successful AWS implementations and to show solidarity with an IT leader&#39;s cause, I recently obtained the AWS Solutions Architect certification. This is just the first step in showcasing various levels of knowledge that Genvega and I can bring to the table for complex IT cloud projects. In future, I plan to take the AWS DevOps Engineer certification test. Watch this space!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Solutions-Architect-Associate.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image showing AWS Solutions Architect - Associate&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;About the AWS Solutions Architect Certification&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AWS &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/certification/&quot;&gt;certifications&lt;/a&gt; test the individual&#39;s ability to design, deploy and operate AWS infrastructure. In particular, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/certification/certified-solutions-architect-associate/&quot;&gt;AWS Solutions Architect certification&lt;/a&gt; tests the individual&#39;s ability to design fault tolerant, scalable systems using AWS. A Certified AWS Solutions Architect is able to analyze business requirements and select the most suitable and cost efficient system design suitable for the requirement. 
&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2016 11:04:43 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.genvega.com/blog/2016/aws-certified-solutions-architect/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.genvega.com/blog/2016/aws-certified-solutions-architect/</guid>
        
        
        <category>announcements</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
